Gautam Varshney

gautamvarshney1999@gmail.com | 952-823-4876 My Instagram Channel | linkedin.com/in/gautam-varshney

About

Web Developer with training and experience in **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **React.js**, **Redux.Js** programming. Knowledgeable in wide range of development languages and methodologies. Bright critical thinker with proven talent for learning quickly in results-oriented environment.

Skills

Languages: C/C++, Java, HTML, CSS, JS.

Technologies & Tools: ReactJS, NodeJs, Bootstrap, ExpressJs, InertiaJs, MongoDB, REST APIs, Redux, Js, Axios, JSON etc.

Work Experience

Lavi Software and Technology, Noida

Jan 2024 - Present

Web Developer

- Created <u>PeSynergy.com</u> a Fintech Company's Website (Freelance).
- Worked on Frontend of https://kanakdrishtiinfo.com/ and https://paysants.com/ company official sites.
- Worked on Frontend of E-commerce Website https://swayamenterprises.com/.
- Worked on Frontend of an E-commerce Website https://clawsarmwrestling.com/.
- Fully Created https://mytaxsavvy.com/ a Website for Tax consultancy and ITR filing (Freelance).

Indsac Softtech Private Limited, Bangalore (Remote)

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

Frontend Developer

- Worked on company's website. Tools using React.js, events, state, hooks, routers, forms, bootstrap, Formik, Yup, Axios, API Calls, Fetch API, Chart.Js, Swiper, Accordion, etc.
- Also worked with Context Api and Global State-Management (redux.js).

MileStoneOS Technologies, Noida

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

Frontend Developer Intern

- Created Three Websites with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React (All the sites are working properly with front-end as well as back-end).
- Food Ordering Website: It Is created with HTML, CSS, JS with interactive UI which take orders as well as create cart for the specific order and user can easily updated cart as per his requirement. It has 4 webpages with responsive Navbar and other interactive elements.
- **Billing System**:- It is the website having three interactive webpages with other responsive elements. It is design to create and update Bills.
- Website for an Industry :- A website with HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap designed with Navbar, Carousel, RTL, Contact Info etc.

Education

C.S.J.M Kanpur (Kanpur University)

Jun 2021 - May 2023

Masters in Computer Application

CGPA:7.3/10

Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Databases, Discrete Mathematics, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Machine Learning, Advance Data Structures and Algorithms, Image Processing.

G.C.M.T (Agra University)

July 2018 - Mar 2021

Bachelor's in Computer Application

CGPA:7.1/10

Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Databases, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks.

Project Work

- **Jewelry Town (business website) (2023):** Fully Functional Responsive Website using React.js, Used Accordion, Swiper ,Hooks, Events, Effects https://varshneygautam17.github.io/React_Website_1/.
- FindMyParking (Parking Management Website) (2023): Created using MERN Stack, UI with Cards, Carousel, Forms and Tables by React-Bootstrap, Advanced features include search, filter, and export-to-CSV, Efficient backend API for searching and managing parking data https://findmyparking.netlify.app/.

Awards and Certificates

• Advanced React From Coursera

• Basic React From Coursera

HTML, CSS, and Javascript
Problem Solving (Basic)
From Hackerrank